

# Samy CHBINOU

DevOps Pipeline Engineer

Imp Juan, ANTIBES, FR

06 67 89 55 87

samy.chbinou@esna.cloud

https://chbinousamy.github.io/resume/resume.pdf

English, Italian, French

# **BACKGROUND**

#### **ABOUT**

51 years old, Telecom & Software engineering education, I worked in software industry on real time embedded applications for mobile phones, IP multimedia set top boxes. I worked in setup Cloud Native infrastructure platforms, DevOps toolchains for CI/CD Worflows and Data processing.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Career Break, Relocation, Antibes 06

Oct. 2021 - Present

DevOps, NAVYA, La Défense 92

Sep, 2021 - Oct, 2021 1 month

NAVYA Drive delivers autonomous driving. In a Agile team of 5 persons I added Gitlab pipelines automation for Continuous Integration Tests. I also setup some Gitlab runners to handle load CI tests. Directly installed on Bare Metal and on some VMs, Virtualbox and AWS

- CI pipelines on Gitlab self hosted runners
- o Docker Buildx Python Containers

## Artificial Intelligence Engineer, VALEO, Créteil 94

May, 2021 - Jul, 2021 1 month

Valeo. In the transversal GEEDS entity, I assist in relocation of the R&D Datacenter from Paris to Créteil.

- Buildx Nvidia python Docker Containers
- o Assistance in relocating a Datacenter from Paris to Creteil

### Platform Engineer, Nokia Bell Labs, Nozay 78

Oct, 2014 - Dec, 2020 6 years 2 months

Nokia Bell Labs. Cloud RAN Entity, Cloud for Radio Access Networks which interconnects radio devices such as Phones, IoT, Automotive, Virtual Reality User Equipments. I worked as freelance in a 'StartUp Garage'. I setup a On-Prems, PaaS context to make some tests on different types of Cloud Native technologies: storage databases, ethernet over fiber, docker containers and kubernetes clusters, Machine Learning DevOps pipelines

- Wrote Statement Of Work définitions with scope of work, project objectives, task schedules and deliverables
- Benchmarking CPU Offloading on Nvidia GPU, Xilinx FPGA
- Benchmarking Ethernet over Optical Fiber (RDMA)
- N-Tiers Microservices Architectures: Docker, NoSQL Databases, Kubernetes, Cloud Native Serverless
- Machine learning and Neural Networks Data engineering

#### Career Break,

Apr, 2013 - Oct, 2014 1 year 5 months

### Software Test Engineer, Ercom, Thales Subsidiary, Vélizy 78

Dec, 2006 - Apr, 2013 6 years 3 months

Ercom is a Thales Subsidiary. I worked in a 10 people Télécom team on Mobipass product, a Functionnal and Stress Test for eNodeB and 4G/LTE Mobiles. As Software engineer, I developped a User Interface in .NET C# language and did many tests on Network Data Encoding and Decoding.

- Integration and Validation Tests
- o Processing Network Datagram Blocks: Cut & Reassemble, Encode & Decode
- C# .NET UI software development
- Functionnal and Stress Tests of eNodeB and 4G/LTE Mobiles

#### SKILLS

#### **Programming Languages** C# .NET Python SQL **YAML JSON HTML** Javascript **DevOps** CI/CD Pipelines Docker Netdata **Platforms AWS EKS GCP GKE Linux ARM** Helm

Telecom and Software Engineering, Engineer, IMT Atlantique (ex Télécom Bretagne)				
Sep, 1994 - Jun, 19	6			
INTERESTS				
Open Source				
Photography				